Joseph SHYIRAMBERE

Nyarugenge, Kigali City, Rwanda



shyirambere2016@gmail.com



+25078 361 9502



linkedin.com/in/shyirambere

Summary

I am a Front End and backend developer with industry experience building websites and web applications. I specialise in JavaScript, Typescript, php and have professional experience working with nodejs and python. I also have experience working with Codelgniter and React.

For database, I could use Mysql and Postgresql (relation database), mongodb (document database) and Redis (caching database).

My programming learning Journal:

- 1. 2012 2014 I started with C, C++, Visual basic and Relational database
- 2. 2016 up to now, I added on above language PHP, Python, Javascript and Java

Some framework I learned to Wordpress, Codelgniter and Prestashop

libraries express js, Typescript,

Web design with HTML, CSS, JQuery, boostrap, tailwind

Experience

Backend dev on Emma Care Foundation website

Universalbridge

Jan 2022 - Present (11 months +)

Care Foundation is a Non Profit Organization registered and Headquartered in Canada with operations in different African countries. This website provides a way of joining organization and website support donation.

It developed in node is with express and react is. It is integrated with paypal to support donation

Website address https://emmacarefoundation.net/



Back End Developer on MWISOKO Project

mwisoko

Sep 2019 - Present (3 years 3 months +)

MWISOKO Project is a Platform to market Small and Medium Businesses using Mobile Phone in Rwanda. A Platform (Network) that enables Youth, Women and other Citizens living in rural areas to collect data and market their different businesses and products by using Mobile Phones and Computers.

During web developer, I was responsible for server-side web application logic and database analysis and design and integration of the work front-end developers do. This system was developed as rest-full API with nodejs with express library and Postgres as relation database.

Back End Developer Fieldforce Rwanda

Universalbridge

Aug 2020 - Oct 2020 (3 months)

Fieldforce Rwanda, this platform help people to align your career. where people will be candidates to any job opportunities. for people to be notified where there is a job.

Website address https://fieldforce.rw/

During system development I worked as both backend. I was responsible for server-side web application logic and database analysis and design, This system was developed as rest-full api with plain php and MySql database.

Back End Developer on Web-based Learning and Assessment Platform

Universalbridge

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020 (3 months)

Web-Based Learning and Assessment Platform (WBLAP) is an online Collaboration board. It is a suitable methodology of teaching and learning propagation of mechanical wave since it facilitates collaboration between teachers and learners within a digital environment. Any user can ask and respond to questions, send a comment as well as develop an argument to benefit the class.

During web developer, I was responsible for server-side web application logic and database analysis and design and integration of the work front-end developers do. This system was developed as rest-full api with nodejs with express library and MySql database

This is web application address https://ephysicsclass.com/

During web developer, I was responsible for server-side web application logic and database analysis and design and integration of the work front-end developers do.

This is web application address https://ephysicsclass.com/

Backend and fronted developer on chemistry secret organisation

Chemsecret Academy

May 2020 - Jun 2020 (2 months)

Chemsecret is web site show publication on a multiscientific topics, medicines and shares the information on the growth opportunities around the globe.

During system development I worked as both backend and frontend developer, it developed in plain PHP, I was responsible for server-side web application logic and database analysis and design , also determining the structure and design of web pages, striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design, and ensuring web design is optimized for smartphones.

The website address is https://chemsecret.org

software development and analysis on Nyambika online collection

Universalbridge

Sep 2019 - May 2020 (9 months)

Nyambika is web application which is like clothes a show room. It a system used by tailors, clothing companies, industries and sewing materials trader to market the products. This system sampling life

where client making sewing order online and each tailors, clothing companies, industries and sewing materials trader has own page shows his/her products, its link his/her address on nyambika.

While web application development I worked as both backend and frontend developer, it developed in plain PHP, I was responsible for server-side web application logic and database analysis and design, also determining the structure and design of web pages, striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design, and ensuring web design is optimized for smartphones.

System address https://ephysicsclass.com/



Software Developer on real estate platform

MD GROUP LTD

Jun 2018 - Sep 2019 (1 year 4 months)

mdgrou is a platform that connects people who want to rent, buy, sell, auction houses, plots, land, real estate and other properties in Rwanda online. This web application is total different with other real estate web application because it has different use types such as individual, company and agent who work under company. Other things are the way of promoting property by positioning it where you want on web site and other setting of boosting it.

During system development I worked as both backend and frontend developer because it was developed with plain PHP, I was responsible for server-side web application logic and determining the structure and design of web pages, striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design, and ensuring web design is optimized for smartphones.

The web application address is https://mdgrou.com

Education



university of Rwanda

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2016 - 2020



Mater dei Nyanza

High School, Mathematics, Physics and Computer Science Jan 2012 - Nov 2014

Skills

DevOps • Python (Programming Language) • REST APIs • Express.js • Agile Methodologies • Redis JavaScript
HTML5
Bootstrap
Maintains an end user focus